(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.1",
"generated_at": "2026-08-12T21:31:20.490699",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
I'm a dreamer
ひそむパワー
A hidden power
私の世界
My world
夢と恋と不安で出来てる
Is made of dreams, love, and anxiety
でも想像もしないもの 隠れてるはず
Yet something unimaginable must be hidden there
空に向かう木々のように
Like trees reaching toward the sky
あなたを まっすぐ見つめてる
I'm looking straight at you
みつけたいなあ
I want to find it...
かなえたいなあ
I want to make it come true...
信じる それだけで 越えられないものはない
Just by believing, there's nothing we cannot overcome
歌うように 奇跡のように
Like a song, like a miracle
「思い」が全てを変えてゆくよ
Our feelings will change everything
きっと きっと 驚くくらい
Surely, surely, enough to amaze you
I'm a dreamer
ひそむパワー
A hidden power
まだ見ぬ世界
In a world yet unseen
そこ何が待っていても
No matter what is waiting there for me
もしも理想と違っても 恐れはしない
Even if it differs from my ideals, I won't be afraid
鳥たちは風にのり 旅をしてゆく
Birds ride on the wind and journey on
今日から明日へと
From today into tomorrow
伝えたいなあ
I want to convey it...
さけびたいなあ
I want to shout it out...
この世に一つだけの存在である私
As someone unique in this world
祈るように 星のように
Like a prayer, like a star
小さな光だけどいつかは
Though a small light, someday
もっと もっと
I want to become
つよくなりたい
Much, much stronger
限界のない可能性がここにある この手に
Limitless potential lies right here in my hands
It's gonna be your world
みつけたいなあ
I want to find it...
かなえたいなあ
I want to make it come true...
信じる それだけで 越えられないものはない
Just by believing, there's nothing we cannot overcome
歌うように 奇跡のように
Like a song, like a miracle
「思い」が全てを変えてゆくよ
Our feelings will change everything
きっと きっと
Surely, surely...
はぁーい！みなさん、こんばんはー！
Hii! Everyone, good evening!
本日、猫又おかゆバースデー3Dライブ2024、キャットフードへようこそー！
Welcome to the Nekomata Okayu Birthday 3D Live 2024, Cat Food!
こちらハッシュタグ、猫又おかゆ生誕祭2024でたくさんポストしてねー！
Be sure to post a lot using the hashtag #NekomataOkayuBirthday2024!
早速ですが、1曲目「プラチナ」歌わせていただきましたー！
Without further ado, we performed our first song, "Platinum"!
この曲はもう、なんと言ってもね、忙しい時にたくさん元気と勇気をもらっていた曲になっています。
This song, you know, no matter what, is a song that gave me so much energy and courage when I was busy.
いっぱい感慨深いなと思いながら歌って踊らせていただきました。
I sang and danced to it while feeling deeply nostalgic.
ていうか、このステージさ、
I mean, this stage, you know—
すっごくなーい！
isn't it amazing?!
Isn't it amazing?!
マジですごいんだよ。
Seriously, it's so amazing!
いや、このステージかわいくてすごいだけじゃなくて、あとになったらこのステージの何がすごいのかライブが終わる頃にわかる仕掛けとなっておりますので、そちらも楽しみにしてて下さい。
I mean, this stage isn't just cute and amazing—later on, you'll find out what makes this stage so special by the end of the live, so please look forward to that too!
一旦はこのステージかわいいなって感じで、このライブ楽しんでいただければなーって思います。
For now, I hope you'll just enjoy the live thinking how cute this stage is.
ちょっとね、含みもあるんですよ。含みといえば、含みといえばですよ。
There's also some hidden meaning to it, you know. Speaking of hidden meaning—
今回のライブのタイトルはキャットフードというタイトルになっておりまして、こちらもいっぱいいっぱい頭をねてねてねてね、思いついたタイトルになってるので、
The title of this live is "Cat Food," and since I came up with this title after racking my brain so much,
このライブのタイトルにもどんな意味があるのかなとか考えながら見てくれると、二倍三倍楽しんでいただけるんじゃないかなって思います。
if you watch while thinking about what kind of meaning this title holds, I think you'll enjoy it two or three times more!
ここから1時間、楽しいこともりだくさんだから、みんな乗り遅れるなよ！
From here on, there's an hour full of fun things, so everyone, don't miss out!
ゲストのみんなの準備も済んだみたいだよ。
It looks like all the guests are ready too.
それじゃあ、引き続き僕のライブ楽しんでね！行ってきまーす！
Well then, please continue to enjoy my live! Here I go!
Smile・Sweet・Sister・Sadistic Surprise・Service We are スティーレ！！
Smile, Sweet, Sister, Sadistic, Surprise, Service, We are Stile!!
さあ 扉 を 開けて 未知 なる パラダイス
Come on, open the door to a paradise unknown,
体験 しよう おいで おいで YOU
experience it—come on, come on, YOU!
そう キミ を 待つ の は 不思議 な オアシス
What awaits you is a mysterious oasis,
ほっこり 日常 に ちょっぴり Spice
a cozy daily life with a little bit of spice!
ぐー るん ぐー るん かきまぜちゃう ん だ
Stir it round and round, mixing it all up—
ぐー るん ぐー るん 当店 自慢 の フレイバー
round and round, our shop's proud flavor!
サービス サービス ご褒美 タイム おもてなし
Service, service, reward time, hospitality
ココロ 込め て Welcome to...
put straight from the heart, Welcome to...
わーい！ わたし 達 と 一緒に めくるめく ワンダー デイドリーム
Yay! A dazzling wonderland dream together with us!
愛情 マシマシ 煩悩 ナデナデ 誠心 誠意 つとめ ます
Overflowing affection, patting away worldly desires, we serve with all our heart and sincerity!
いえー す ！ キミ の 元気 チャージ に ひと役 かえる かな
Yes! Can we play a part in recharging your energy?
こー いった 感じ も あー いった 感じ も 意外と 悪く ない でしょ ？
This kind of vibe, or that kind of vibe—isn't it surprisingly not bad?
Buono Buono ブレンド し たい キミ に きゅんきゅんきゅん ハート に ぱんち ぱんち ぱんち
Buono, Buono, I want to blend—punch, punch, punch right into your heart filled with doki-doki!
Buono Buono ブレンド し たい お口 に あい ます か ？ お口 に あう と いい な ♪
Buono, Buono, I want to blend—does it suit your palate? I hope it suits your taste ♪
ぽなぺてぃーと
Bon Appétit!
ぽなぺてぃーと 千客 万来 らーい ！
Bon Appétit! Customers coming by the thousands, rah-rah!
ちょっと 、 なんか 、 不本意 ながら も いつだって 需要 は 斜め 上
Even if it's somewhat against my will, demand is always diagonally upward!
そんじゃ 、 いっか 、 ホント の わたし は シークレット モード で 営業 スイッチ オン
Well then, whatever, the real me turns on the business switch in secret mode!
ぐー るん ぐー るん かきまぜて もっと ぐー るん ぐー るん キミ 仕様 の フレイバー
Stir it round and round even more—round and round, a flavor tailored just for you!
サービス サービス 極上 タイム 癒し と は かく ある べき Welcome to...
Service, service, supreme time, healing should be just like this, Welcome to...
わーい！ わたし 達 の お店 に 本日 も ようこそ おかえり 待ってた リピート うれしい な
Yay! Welcome once again to our shop today! Welcome back, we were waiting, so happy for a repeat!
店員 一同 歓迎 一度 乾杯 ！
All staff welcome you, a toast once more!
Smile!
Sweet!
Sister!
Sadistic!
Surprise!
Service!
We are スティーレ！！
We are Stile!!
さあ扉を開けて
Come on, open the door!
未知なるパラダイス 体験しよう
Experience the unknown paradise!
（おいで おいで YOU）
(Come on, come on YOU)
そう キミを待つのは 不思議なオアシス
That's right, waiting for you is a mysterious oasis
（ほっこり日常に ちょっとぱりSpice）
(A little bit of spice in your cozy daily life)
ぐーるんぐーるん 当店自慢のフレーバー
Whirling, whirling, our shop's proud flavor
サービスサービス ご褒美タイム
Service, service, a rewarding time
おもてなし ココロこめて
With all our hearts, welcoming you
Welcome to…
Welcome to...
わーい！ 私達と一緒にめくるめくワンダーデイリーーム
Hooray! A dizzying wonder day-dream together with us!
愛情マシマシ 煩悩ナデナデ 誠心誠意つとめます
More and more affection, stroking away worldly desires, we will serve you with all our sincerity!
いーース！ キミの元気チャージにひと役かえるかな
Yes!! I wonder if I can play a part in charging up your energy?
こーいう感じも あーいう感じも
Whether it's this kind of feeling or that kind of feeling,
意外と悪くないでしょ？
Isn't it unexpectedly not bad?
Buono Buono ブレンドしたい♪
Buono, Buono, I want to blend! ♪
キミにきゅん♡きゅん♡きゅん♡
Thumping, thumping, thumping for you
ハートにぱんち！ぱんち！ぱんち！
Punch, punch, punch to your heart!
（ぱんち！ぱんち！ぱんち！）
(Punch, punch, punch!)
Buono Buono ブレンドしたい♪
Buono, Buono, I want to blend! ♪
お口にあいますか？
Does it suit your taste?
お口にあうといいな♪
I hope it suits your taste ♪
ぼなぺてぃーと♡ ぼなぺてぃーと♡ ぼなぺてぃーと♡
Bon appétit! Bon appétit! Bon appétit!
千客ばんばんらいっ！
A flood of customers, hurrah!
ちょっと、なんか、不本意ながらも
Even though it's somewhat against my will,
いつだって需要は斜め上
Demand is always off the charts
そんじゅ、いっか、ホントのわたしは
Well, whatever, the real me is
シークレットモードで営業スイッチオン
Turning on the business switch in secret mode
ぐーるんぐーるん かきまぜて もっと
Whirling, whirling, stirring some more
ぐーるんぐーるん キミ仕様のフレーバー
Whirling, whirling, a flavor customized for you
サービスサービス 極上タイム
Service, service, supreme time
癒やしとは かくあるべき
Healing is how it should be
Welcome to…
Welcome to...
わーい！ 私達のお店に本日もようこそ
Hooray! Welcome once again to our shop today
おかえり待ってた リピートうれしいな
Welcome back, I was waiting, repeats make me so happy
店員一同歓迎
All the staff welcome you
いーース！ キミのお疲れ様にピッタリのレシピで
Yes!! With a recipe perfect for your tiredness
こーゆーのどうかな？ あーゆーのありかな？
How about something like this? Is something like that okay?
よろこんできてくれるかな？
I wonder if you're happy with it?
Smile・Sweet・Sister・Sadistic
Smile, sweet, sister, sadistic
Small・Strange・Serious・Selfish
Small, strange, serious, selfish
Secret・Super Girl We are スティーレ！！
Secret, super girl, we are Stile!!
さあ扉を開けて 愉快なパラダイス
Come on, open the door to a joyful paradise
怖がらずにおいで、おいで
Don't be afraid, come on, come on
そう、いつも通りの毎日に イロドリとアソビゴコロ
Yes, add color and a playful heart to your usual everyday routine
召し上がれ ブレンド・S
Bon appétit, Blend S
Welcome to…
Welcome to...
わーい！ 私達と一緒にめくるめくワンダーデイリーーム
Hooray! A dizzying wonder day-dream together with us!
愛情マシマシ 煩悩ナデナデ 誠心誠意つとめます
More and more affection, stroking away worldly desires, we will serve you with all our sincerity!
いーース！ キミの元気チャージにひと役かえるかな
Yes!! I wonder if I can play a part in charging up your energy?
こーいう感じも あーいう感じも
Whether it's this kind of feeling or that kind of feeling,
意外と悪くないでしょ？
Isn't it unexpectedly not bad?
Buono Buono ブレンドしたい♪
Buono, Buono, I want to blend! ♪
キミにきゅん♡きゅん♡きゅん♡
Thumping, thumping, thumping for you
ハートにぱんち！ぱんち！ぱんち！
Punch, punch, punch to your heart!
（ぱんち！ぱんち！ぱんち！）
(Punch, punch, punch!)
Buono Buono ブレンドしたい♪
Buono, Buono, I want to blend! ♪
お口にあいますか？
Does it suit your taste?
お好み聞かせてね
Let me hear your preferences
お口にあうといいな♪
I hope it suits your taste ♪
社長 お誕生日おめでとうございます！
Manager, happy birthday!
おめでとうございますー！
Congratulations!
いや、びっくり社員集合嬉しすぎる！
Yay, we have way too many store employees!
おめでとうおかゆさん どうしたの？
Manager Okayu, what's going on?
今日は特別に私達がプレゼントを用意しました
Today, we have a special present prepared from all of us!
え、なに？
Eh? What?
えー、今日はですね、私たち1人1人がですね
Well, today, each and every one of us...
なんと社長の妹になることになりました！
has become the manager's younger sister!
えーー！？ 妹ーー！？
Ehー?! Younger sister?!
ま、ちょっと恥ずかしいけど
Well, it's a bit embarrassing, but...
まあ、社長は物よりこういうシチュエーションの方が喜ぶんじゃないかっていう
well, for a manager, having cute younger sisters is more pleasing, right?
そうだね。うん。
That's right.
正解すぎるけど。
Is it correct?
喜んでる。喜んでる。
Glad you're happy.
はい、じゃあここからやる、やってくれる？
Alright then, let's start doing it from here, will you do it?
じゃあ頼むよ。先陣を切って。じゃあじゃあじゃあ妹になるとここにきてください。
Okay, let's go. First one, please.
お願いしまーす。はい。仕切り直した。
Please.
おかゆおねえちゃん。
Okayu Onee-chan.
何してたの？ どこ行ってたの？
What were you doing? Where were you going?
ほかのお人間の匂いがするよ。消毒しないとね。
Someone's scent lingers... You need to disinfect!
消毒、消毒。一緒に お風呂、あ、かわいい、うれしい、うれしい！
Disinfect, disinfect! Let's take a bath together!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
ヤンデレ妹だ。
That's a Yandere younger sister...
次誰来てくれるんだろ？次誰来てくれるんだ？本物のお、本物の妹来た！
Who is the next one who's going to come? Next who is going to come?
これ偽物だぞ、みたいなやつだよ。うちらが偽物、偽物。
This is a fake one, right? Like a fake.
おねえちゃん、お誕生日おめでとう！
Onee-chan, happy birthday!
ん、ありがとう。プレゼントー！
Thank you, presentー!
やばい。
That's crazy.
あのゲームの先輩でありながら自分の妹にするっていうハイテク感がね、いいですよね。
Being a gamer's senior while also being your younger sister is a nice high-spec feeling, isn't it?
かわいい。次誰なんだ？次はいったい誰なんだ？はい！
So cute. Next, who is coming? Next, who is coming?
いつもママなみおちゃんだ。
It's always Mama Mio-chan!
お、おねえちゃん。
Onee-chan...
えっと、あの、いつも、あの、うちのこと、でももっと甘えてほしいな。
Um, you know...
かわいい！ こっちでも甘えていいよ。
Cute! Pamper me more!
おねえちゃん。
Onee-chan...
うわ、かわいい！
So cute!
なんか、姉妹じゃなくて、なんか、お互いの時とテンションが逆転して、やっぱ、甘えたかったんだなっていう実、実はね、ママ系妹でした、最後に。
It feels like a real sister...
ママ系妹のコマか、この流れ。
Mama...
最後に、おかゆのターンが来ました。
Finally, finally, Okayu's turn has come.
やめて、待って、もっと早くおかゆ。
Wait, wait, I want to go faster!
おかゆ、はいはいはい。おかゆのターンで、おかゆは、あ、妹どこかな、妹どこかな？
Okay, okay, Okayu's turn. For Okayu's turn, Okayu is...
おねえちゃん、早く起きてよ！
Onee-chan, please wake up!
おでんできたよ、おでん！
Oden is ready, oden!
おでんでつちだね。もっともっとかわ…
Oden for a younger sister is...
おでんはダメだって。おでんはダメだって。おでんはダメ…
Oden is no good, oden is no good.
ちょっとリクエストが強すぎ、強すぎじゃないかっていうさ。
Well, the request is too strong, isn't it?
おねえちゃん！
Onee-chan!
あ、かわいい！ 妹きた！
Ah, cute! The younger sister has come!
大好き！
I love you!
恥ずかしいよー！
So embarrassing!
恥ずかしいよ？
Embarrassing?
なんか変だよ？
Something's weird, right?
すっごい生まれたてことに…乾杯！
A toast... to being freshly born!
はい、乾杯！乾杯乾杯！
Cheers! Cheers, cheers!
はいお疲れ様。行くよ。
Good work. Let's go.
微妙に気持ち悪かったよね？
That felt subtly creepy, right?
もっと一人でいいだろ！
You should just do it alone!
いまだって……さあ行こっか。
Even now... Well, let's go.
待ち侘びている 大通り
Waiting on the main street,
目眩しそうな 人込み
in the blinding crowd,
くるり回った 昼帯
spinning around in broad daylight.
立ち止まってる ぽっぽ
Standing still, poppo.
しまい切れてない 表情
An expression you can't quite hide,
どこ見てるの ぽっぽ
where are you looking, poppo?
知らない 今 なに
I don't know, what is this now?
目と目止まった 合図
Eyes met, a stopped signal.
ロングの ローリーズ 「あとでね」 黒文字
Long lolita... "Later," in black text.
隠しても ムダね
Even if you hide it, it's useless.
けけけけーたいみしてよ 今から
Show me your phone right now!
ねえ 今から ねえ 今から
Hey, right now, hey, right now!
ねえ いいでしょ けーたいみしてよ
Hey, please? Show me your phone!
拒んでるの 予想通り
Refusing just as expected,
だって賭けたこの試み
because I bet on this attempt.
くるり回った 昼帯
spinning around in broad daylight,
立ち止まらないで
don't just stand there.
怒ったりしないでよ
Don't get mad at me,
i need チュチュチュチュ
I needchu-chu-chu!
いらない いらない
I don't need it, I don't need
使い古しの愛も 言い訳たちも
worn-out love or excuses.
画面じゃなく ここ見て 取り上げるからね
Look here, not at the screen, 'cause I'm taking it!
けけけけーたいみしてよ 今から
Show me your phone right now!
ねえ 今から ねえ 今から
Hey, right now, hey, right now!
ねえ いいでしょ けーたいかしてよ 今から
Hey, please? Lend me your phone right now!
けけけけーたいかしてよ 今から
Lend me your phone right now!
ねえ 今すぐ 渡しなさい ねえ いいでしょ
Hey, hand it over right now, hey, please?
けーたいみしてよ
Show me your phone!
Lonely ロリロリ神、降臨
Lonely loli-loli god, descending,
鐘を鳴らせばこの通り
if you ring the bell, it's just like this.
これは救済のレクイエム
This is a requiem of salvation.
触ったら逮捕！極chu❤de!点呼! (Uh!)
Touch and you're arrested! Extreme chu❤de roll call!
いちにーさんしー? (ごめんなさーい)
One, two, three, four? (I'm sorryー!)
はあ?(ﾟДﾟ)ごめんなさいが、聞こえなーい(え~!)
Huh?(ﾟДﾟ) I can't hear your apology (Eh~!)
粛聖!! ロリ神レクイエム
Purification!! Loli God Requiem
将来はお前なんかに好かれたくない (ない!)
I never want someone like you to like me!
泥水で口を洗え 法廷で会おう?❤ (ねっ)
Wash your mouth out with muddy water, see you in court?❤
さあ おまわりさん 連れて行って 妄想しか取り柄のない かわいそうな人
Now, officer, take away this pathetic person whose only redeeming quality is delusion.
うわ、ありがとう お疲れ様です~^^
Woah, thank you, good work~^^
ロリロリ神、降臨 (ずっきゅーん!)
Loli-loli god, descending (Zukyuun!)
奴等に用心 (ばっきゅーん!)
Watch out for those scumbags (Bakyuun!)
まともじゃないなら 早く消えてください
If you're not decent, hurry up and disappear.
ロリロリ神、降臨 (ずっきゅーん!)
Loli-loli god, descending (Zukyuun!)
鐘を鳴らせばこの通り (Yes! Yes! Yes!)
If you ring the bell, it's just like this (Yes! Yes! Yes!)
とても優しくて 素敵なお兄ちゃん
Such a very kind and wonderful big brother.
楽園でホラ ねんねしな (ねんねしな~)
In paradise, hey, go to sleep (Go to sleep~)
ほら、世の中には、こんなに気持ち悪い人たちが跋扈しているんですっ！
Look, the world is crawling with such creepy people!
みんな、晒し上げますよ！
I'm gonna expose you all!
触ったら逮捕！極chu❤de!点呼!
Touch and you're arrested! Extreme chu❤de roll call!
いちにーさんしー? (ごめんなさーい)
One, two, three, four? (I'm sorryー!)
はあ?(ﾟДﾟ)
Huh?(ﾟДﾟ)
ごめんなさいが、聞こえなーい! 粛聖!! ロリ神レクイエム
I can't hear your apology! Purification!! Loli God Requiem
はーい、獄中にいるみんなしゃーん、刑務所…
Hii, everyone in prison, prison...
刑務所ファンミーティングのお時間でぇす
It's time for the prison fan meeting!
その腐りきった耳をゴリゴリカッポジって
Clean out those rotted ears of yours,
よーく聴いてくださいね
and listen closely, okay?
ざーこ
Trash.
キムキモ
Gross.
うるさい
Shut up.
黙ってもらっていいですか？
Would you mind shutting up?
嫌いです
I hate you.
かわいい
Cute.
だーい よーわ みっともな～いｗ
You guys are so pathetic, lol.
どうしようもない お兄ちゃん お姉ちゃん
Hopeless big brothers and big sisters,
もう希望もない ゴミ箱 おめぇら
with no hope left, you pieces of garbage.
怪物消毒 110番
Monster disinfection, dial 110.
固有結界 発動！
Reality marble, activate!
収聖おかビーム！！
Syukusei Oka-beam!!
もういっちょ、しーぴービーム！！
One more time, CP-beam!!
まだまだ、あみやビーム！！
Still not done, Amiya-beam!!
怒りの日。聖なるインターネットに、血の雨が降り注いだ日。
The day of wrath. When a rain of blood fell upon the sacred internet.
愚かなロリコンを骨の髄まで浄化する、一筋の光。
A single ray of light purifying foolish lolicons to the bone.
それが、おかビームなのである。
That is the Oka-beam.
あみやは、全てを救いします…
Amiya will save everything...
ああ この世の醜さを 集めて描いてみるよ
Ah, collecting the ugliness of this world, I'll try to paint it.
真っ白なキャンバスが 汚れて泣いている
A pure white canvas is stained and crying.
Lonely 振り向いた少女を そっと手を掴む…
Lonely, she turns around, and I gently take her hand...
『楽園など無いから』
"Because there is no paradise."
おっきなお友達のみんなぇ
To all you big kids out there,
お前らが打ち込んでいる虚無には 何の意味があるの？
what's the point of the emptiness you're typing away?
ねぇ、教えてよ。ぼく、ぜんぜんわかんないんだ！
Hey, tell me. I don't get it at all!
瑠璃々々込み来わり
Ruri-ruri entangled,
さよなら笑顔でぱっきゅーん！ ピリオドをどうぞこの手で推してあげる
Goodbye with a smiley, bang-kyun! Here's your period, pushed by my own hand.
ラブリールリリリ神来臨
Lovely ruri-ruri-ruri god descending,
鐘を鳴らせばこの通り
ringing the bell just like this!
とても優しくて 素敵なお兄ちゃん 楽園でホラ ねんねしな
Such a very kind, wonderful big brother. Now go to sleep in paradise.
それが救済の レクイエム
That is the requiem of salvation.
触ったら逮捕 ごくちゅうでてんこ
Touch me and you're arrested, roll call in prison!
いちにさんしー？ (はぁ？)
One, two, three, four? (Huh?)
ごめんなさいが、聞こえなーい！えー！？
I can't hear your "I'm sorry"! Ehー!?
収聖ロリ神レクイエム☆
Syukusei Loli God Requiem☆
ほんとに、きもちわるい。
Honestly, you're so creepy.
お誕生日おめでとう！
Happy birthday!
うれしすぎる、ありがとうございます！
I'm so happy, thank you so much!
やめてやめて
Stop it, stop it!
初めて土下座した
I bowed to the ground for the first time.
どういう状況これ？
What kind of situation is this?
知ってるでしょ、僕がアミヤのお下がりだの何だの
You know, talking about me wearing Amiya's hand-me-downs...
こうなっちゃんだ！
It ended up like this!
ちょっと本当に可愛すぎて、もうライブに呼ばれるってなって
She was just too cute, and when she got invited to the live,
もうなんか権力使っちゃってるやん
she was like, using her power!
うれしい、ほんとに可愛すぎる、どうしよう
I'm so happy, she's so cute, what should I do?
じゃあ写真でも撮ります？
Well, shall we take a picture?
いいのかな？撮っちゃってもいいのかな？
Is it okay? Is it really okay to take one?
いや二人で撮ります？いやいや三人で撮ろうよ
No, let's take it as two? No, let's take it with three!
一人ずつ？
One by one?
じゃあやっぱシンプルにね、ピースとかどうですか？
Then let's keep it simple, like a peace sign, what do you think?
はいちーず かわいい
Say cheese. So cute.
あとどうしようかな、なんでもやりたいこと言ってね
What else should we do? Tell me anything you want to do.
なんでも？なんでも？なんでもやめとこ
Anything? Anything? Let's drop 'anything'.
やばいやつだからね
Because she's a dangerous one.
この後ろのモニターのイラストを再現するのどう？ すっごい可愛いこれ
How about recreating the illustration on the monitor behind us? It's super cute.
あみやちゃんがこう、かわいい
Amiya-chan like this, so cute.
しいなさんも、もっとゴミを、ゴミを見るような目でしいなさんも見てって
Shiina-san too, look with eyes like you're looking at garbage, Shiina-san too!
ああ、可愛い可愛い可愛いね
Ah, cute, cute, cute, cute.
あと1個僕やりたいことあるんですけど、いいですか？
And I have one more thing I want to do, is that okay?
しいなさんとあみやちゃんで、ハートを作ってもらっていいですか？
Can Shiina-san and Amiya-chan make a heart together?
ハート！すごーい！可愛い！そこにちょっと失礼して
Heart! Wow! So cute! Pushing in right there...
ああ、よかったです！いいねー、よかった！満足！
Ah, I'm so glad! Nice, wonderful! Satisfied!
ちょ、ちょっと待った
Hold on, wait a second!
いや、本当に僕が...
Well, actually, I...
今日ね、あの、あみやちゃんにさ
Today, you know... um, to Amiya-chan,
自前のさ、あみやちゃんのアクリルスタンドを持ってきてサインしてもらおうかなって思ったんだけどさ
I brought my own Amiya-chan acrylic stand thinking I'd get it signed, but...
しののさんがさっき言ったように、ちょっと、ね、権力使いすぎかなって
As Shinono-san said earlier, maybe I'm abusing my power a bit...
権力？
Power?
思って... やめといたんだよ、あみやちゃん！
Thinking that... I decided against it, Amiya-chan!
え、そんなことないよ！いくらでも描く、いくらでも描くって！
Eh, that's not true! I'll draw as many as you want!
いる？
Do you want them?
いるよ、いるよ、いるよ！めちゃめちゃいるよ！
There are, there are, there are! There are tons!
シーナのが いつでも
Shiina can anytime in my place
あたしのも いつでもいくらでも描くって
I'll draw anytime as much as you want too!
いる？
Do you want them?
え、いらない
Eh, I don't need them.
反応...
Reaction...
シーナさんもね、シーナさんも、あの、今日、ロリー初めてやってみたと思うんだけど、どうだった？
Shiina-san too, Shiina-san too, um, today you tried loli fashion for the first time, how was it?
あそこにあるよ、見てくれた？
It's over there, did you see it?
ロリーね、めちゃめちゃ頑張った、無理したちょっと
Loli style... I tried so hard, pushed myself a bit.
え、いや、可愛かったよ！めっちゃ可愛かった！
Eh, but it was cute! Super cute!
え？新たな扉を開いた、開いた、開いた、開いてたか
Eh? Opening a new door... opened, opened, opened! Were you used to it?
いや、ロリーシーナめっちゃ良かった
No, Loli Shiina was really good.
ロリーシーナ？
Loli Shiina?
可愛いよ、なんかね
Super cute, you know...
いや、続けてほしい、強制的にロリーにさせられて
Yeah, I want you to keep doing it. Forced to do loli style...
え？
Eh?
可愛いよ、本当
It's cute, really.
いやもう、危ないから帰りましょう
Yeah, it's dangerous, let's go home.
危ない？
Dangerous?
危ないから帰りましょう！おめでとうね！おめでとう！おめでとう！おめでとう！
It's dangerous, let's go home! Congratulations! Congrats! Congrats! Congrats!
おめでとう！ありがとう！
Congratulations! Thank you!
いや、マジで可愛かったね
Man, that was so cute.
いや本当にあの、2、3時のファンの方もたくさん見てるかと思うんですけどね
Yeah, and I think a lot of fans who are up at 2-3 AM are watching...
ありがとうございましたー！
Thank you very much!
お昼にテレビ見ながら食べたあのポテト
i ate those fries while watching tv at lunchtime
この部屋から動けなくなって現実逃避
i couldn’t leave the room, an escape from reality
バンズ パティ マスタード
buns, patty, mustard,
ケチャップ チーズ いってらっしゃい
ketchup, cheese, have a great day
朝 早起きのご褒美 片手にいってらっしゃい
morning, my reward for getting up early, in my hand, have a great day
ギリカツ生きてる毎日
barely making it through each day
怒られたら残機減る
they get mad at me and i lose a life
できること褒めてくれたらはうんあっぷ
praise me for the things i can do, and i get a 1up
僕はニコッとスマイルあげないぜ
i ain’t gonna smile for you
僕は僕のままのキャラクターで
i’m my own character
世界をジワっとあげちゃうぜ
i’m gonna sizzle up the world
そこへ僕は塩を振る
and sprinkle salt on it
僕はニコッとスマイルあげないぜ
i ain’t gonna smile for you
サクッとこなすお茶の子さいさい
i crush my to-dos — piece of cake
やっぱ足りてない協調性だけど
i knew it, not cooperative enough
僕は指揮を振る
i’ll lead the charge though
ルールも知らずに突っ込んでくプレイヤーよ
a player who rushes in not knowing the rules
死なないためのマニュアルかなきゃゲームオーバー
without a manual so you don’t die, you’ll get a game over
人とコミュニケーションは難しいだけど出来気がするテレパシー
communicating is hard, but i feel like i can do telepathy
作業にハマれば意外と楽しいそして褒めてもらえたらちょっと嬉しい
when i’m right for the job, it’s surprisingly fun, and praise makes me kinda happy
チキン、チキン、ナゲット、ナゲット、バーベキュー
chicken, chicken, nugget, nugget, barbecue
チキン、チキン、ナゲット、ナゲット、マスタード
chicken, chicken, nugget, nugget, mustard
ハッピーハッピーセットにはお宝
in happy happy meals there’s treasure
ピクルス抜きにもカスタマイズ
you can even remove the pickles, customize it
ギリカツ生きてる毎日
barely making it through each day
怒られたら残機減る
they get mad at me and i lose a life
できること褒めてくれたらはうんあっぷ
praise me for the things i can do, and i get a 1up
僕はニコッとスマイルあげないぜ
i ain’t gonna smile for you
僕は僕のままのキャラクターで
i’m my own character
世界をジワっとあげちゃうぜ
i’m gonna sizzle up the world
そこへ僕は塩を振る
and sprinkle salt on it
僕はニコッとスマイルあげないぜ
i ain’t gonna smile for you
サクッとこなすお茶の子さいさい
i crush my to-dos — piece of cake
やっぱ足りてない協調性だけど
i knew it, not cooperative enough
僕は指揮を振る
i’ll lead the charge though
いつかニコッと素直になれますか
will i be able to smile and mean it someday?
今はスマイルあげられない
i can’t smile for you right now
それ本気でやってんの
Are you really doing this seriously?
ねえおばけを舐めてんの
Hey, are you underestimating ghosts?
また枕元立ってんの何回やってんの
Standing by my pillow again, how many times is this?
「ほら、怖がれ」という態度
The attitude of "Come on, be scared,"
「怖がって欲しい」という展望
and the expectation that you'll be scared.
あなたはどっちかな？
Which one are you?
神はおっしゃるどっちでもいい
God says either is fine.
心霊写真はウケねらい 誰でもわかるウケねらい
Psychic photos aimed for laughs, obvious to anyone.
渋い呪いもウケねらい 玄人向けたウケねらい
Subtle curses for laughs, aimed at connoisseurs.
てっとりばやく恐怖与えたい
I want to give terror quickly,
日進月歩恐怖磨きたい
and constantly polish my terror day by day.
よそはよそうちはうち 鬼は外から福は内
Others are others, we are us. Demons out, fortune in!
自分がない自分がないから浮かばれない
Having no self, having no self, so I can't find peace.
持論がある持論があるから報われたい
Having a theory, having a theory, so I want to be rewarded.
流行りに乗ってるけど好きでやってんのね
Riding the trend, but doing it because you love it?
それとも魂売って自分殺してんの
Or selling your soul and killing your true self?
ひゅ〜どろどろ ひゅ〜どろどろ
Hyu~ dorodoro, hyu~ dorodoro...
滑ってるのにみんなは称賛
Even though it flops, everyone praises it.
日々労働をのち法要を
Daily labor, followed by memorial services.
続けますわたしの好きなウケねらいを
I will continue my favorite pursuit of laughs!
じんわり火が灯る
A fire slowly ignites,
ローソク吹き消し
blowing out the candle.
大音量のラップ音で すべてが台無し
With loud rapping sounds, everything is ruined.
ありがち？ いやスタンダード 斬新？ いや出オチ
Cliché? No, standard. Novel? No, a one-joke gag.
心霊スポットのレビュー 怨念の考察
Reviews of haunted spots, analysis of grudges.
その方法は受け入れない
That method? I won't accept it.
胡散臭いから受け入れない
It feels fishy, so I won't accept it.
その発想は受け入れたい 不器用だけど受け入れたい
I want to accept that idea, clumsy as it is.
効率よくテキトーに化けたい 損するけどディテール詰めたい
I want to transform casually yet efficiently, but detail it despite losses.
事件がない事件がないからリアルじゃない
No incidents, no incidents, so it doesn't feel real.
危険がある危険があるからみんなは期待
There is danger, there is danger, so everyone expects it.
悪霊のいってる感じ わざと出してんのね
The evil spirit vibe, are you putting it on purpose?
それとも根っから天才でぶっ飛ばしてんの
Or are you just naturally a genius out of your mind?
ひゅ〜どろどろ ひゅ〜どろどろ
Hyu~ dorodoro, hyu~ dorodoro...
喋ってたのにあえなく降参
Even though we were talking, an ignominious surrender.
意気揚々と死後ひょうひょうと
High-spiritedly, and afterlife-wise, breezily.
わかってるのにやめられぬウケねらいよ
Even though I know, I can't stop this pursuit of laughs!
生前から引いてばっかりのはずれくじ
Drawing nothing but losing lots ever since I was alive.
好きだったおばけはどっか行って神隠し
The ghost I loved went somewhere and was spirited away.
やったもん勝ちの許せるラインがぼやけだし 大嫌いなオカルトをみんなが好きでもそういうもんだし
The acceptable line of 'finders keepers' blurs, and even if everyone likes the occult I hate, that's just how it is.
自分がない自分がないから浮かばれない
Having no self, having no self, so I can't find peace.
持論がある持論があるから報われたい
Having a theory, having a theory, so I want to be rewarded.
流行りに乗ってるけど好きでやってんのね
Riding the trend, but doing it because you love it?
それとも魂売って自分殺してんの
Or selling your soul and killing your true self?
ひゅ〜どろどろ ひゅ〜どろどろ
Hyu~ dorodoro, hyu~ dorodoro...
滑ってるのにみんなは称賛
Even though it flops, everyone praises it.
ひゅ〜どろどろ ひゅ〜どろどろ
Hyu~ dorodoro, hyu~ dorodoro...
喋ってたのにあえなく降参
Even though we were talking, an ignominious surrender.
ひゅ〜どろどろ ひゅ〜どろどろ
Hyu~ dorodoro, hyu~ dorodoro...
日々労働>日々労働をのち法要を
Daily labor, followed by memorial services.
意気揚々と死後ひょうひょうと
High-spiritedly, and afterlife-wise, breezily.
続けますわたしの好きなウケねらいを
I will continue my favorite pursuit of laughs!
ばぁ〜
Boo~!
あーもうやめやめやめやめやめやめやめてやめてやめて
Ah, stop, stop, stop, stop it already!
というわけで突然ですが
So anyway, all of a sudden,
ゲマズバラエティコーナー！
Gamers Variety Corner!
お前ら本当に地獄好きだな編
The "You Guys Really Love Hell" Arc!
全部好きじゃないか！
You love all of it!
ということで改めて
So, to start over...
このステージがどういう作りかと言うと、オチのある話をすると床が落ちる仕組みとなっております。
this stage has a mechanic where if you give a lame answer, the floor drops out!
えー！
Oh, come on!
そんな簡単に落ちんやろって！
You really think it's that easy to fall?
いや、まあね、まあそんな簡単には落ちないですよね、フブキさんね。
Well, I mean, it's not that easy to fall, right, Fubuki-san?
どこ行くのみよ？
Where are you going?
どこ行くのみよ、どこ行くのみよ！
Where are you going, Mio?
えいっ！
Hey!
うわああああああ！！！！
Whoa-whoa-whoa-whoa-whoa!
ふぶにゃん？！
Fubu-nyan?!
落ちたー！！
She fell!
なんでテストステージで落としたの！
Why did you drop me into the test stage?!
まあ、そういうわけでね、えー！
Well, you see...
この後のLIVEパートにね、盛り上げて繋げるためにも、精一杯オチをつけて、皆さん頑張ってくださいね。
To really hype things up for the live part later, give us your best punchline, everyone!
よっしゃ、よっしゃ！
Okay, okay!
よっしゃ、よっしゃ、はいはい！
失敗した人はオチをつけるまで残ってもらいますからね。
Anyone who fails has to stay here until they land a punchline, okay?
まじで？本当に。やめてくれ！
Seriously? Just stop it!
まず最初のお題はこちら！
First topic right here!
YAGOOがギリギリ言わなさそうなセリフ。
Things YAGOO would barely not say.
はい！
Alright!
ころね！
Korone!
まだいたんですか。
"Are you still here?"
ギリ言わなさそう～w
He would totally barely say that!
ころねオチた～！！
Korone fell!
やった～！！やったよぉ～！！
I did it! I did it!
冷たいYAGOOは嫌だ！
I don't want a cold YAGOO...
はいはいはい！おかゆさん！
Okay, okay, Okay! Okay, Okayu!
これ自信あります。
I'm confident in this one.
ミオさん…はみ出てます。
"Mio-san... you're sticking out."
何が？
What?
何がですか…？w
What is that supposed to mean?!
今ウケてたのに～！
It was getting a laugh!
おかゆの手前にに入れたい。
I want to put it right in front of Okayu.
おかゆの手前に入れる感じで、あの…
It's like putting it right in front of Okayu, so...
ミオちゃ、ミオさん、
Mio-chan, Mio-san...
ミオさん…はみ出てます。
Mio-san, you're sticking out.
はい次のお題いきま～す！
Alright, next topic!
なんでぇええ～！！！
Why?!
はい、というわけで次のお題はこちらです。
Alright, so the next topic is this!
白上フブキ「赤いなぁ」何を見て言った？
Shirakami Fubuki: "So red." What was she looking at?
フブキタイムスタート！
Let's start!
はい白上さん！
Alright, Shirakami-san!
ミオのパンツ。
"Mio's panties."
白上どーーーん！！！
Shirakami down!
やったーー！！
I did it!
そのパンツは赤くない！落としてもずる！
Those pants are never red! Even if you drop me, that's wrong!
あっ分かった！！
Ah, I get it!
お、分かった？
Oh, you get it?
なんか背中に違和感あるなぁ…
"Somehow my back feels a bit weird..."
「ん？」あ、かい～な。
"Ah, it's itchy."
あぁ、うまいね！
Oh, nice!
おかゆ、オトティ！
Okayu, that's a point!
やったーー！！
I did it!
やったね！
Nice point!
やられるうぅー！！
You're getting me!
赤いよ！
"It's red!"
次のお題はこちら！
Next topic is this!
9999億円かけて新スタジオが設立！衝撃の設備とは？
A new studio established for 99.9 billion yen! What is its shocking feature?
衝撃のタイムスタート！
Let's start!
はい！はい、白上。
Alright, Shirakami!
メカYAGOOがお茶を運んでくれる。
"Mecha YAGOO delivers your tea."
よく見るよね、飲食店で。
You see that a lot at restaurants!
かわいい。メカYAGOO採用～！
That's cute. Mecha YAGOO adopted!
やったー！
Yay!
はい！じゃあ、です。
Alright. Korone-san.
字合ってるかな？
Did I spell it right?
政府。
"The government."
どういうこと…？
What does that mean...?
え、政府の人がいる…
Like, government officials are there...
もはや？もはや、政府の人…がってこと？
You mean "government officials"?
ちょっとシュールですね。もうちょっと言葉が欲しかったですねえ。
That's surreal... I wish you had used a few more words.
あぁ🎁ぁぁぁ！！はいは～い！
Here we go!
はい、おかゆん。
Okayu!
9999億円かけたら、みんなに僕たちのにおいが伝わるー！
"If you spend 99.9 billion yen, our scent will reach everyone."
ええーー！！それはやばい！
What?! That's crazy!
すごい設備ー！！
Amazing facility!
これいいんじゃない？
Isn't that nice?
わぁぁぁ！！
Whoa!
みんな欲しいよねぇ？
Everyone wants that, right?
においはすごいなぁ。
That scent is amazing, though.
はいよ。
Alright.
はい、ころね。
Okay, Korone.
それは何かの間違い。
"You've got that all wrong."
お金そんなかけられないから！
"We can't spend that much money!"
確かにそれはそう。
That's true, though.
落とせぇ～！！リアリストですねぇ！
Drop her! She's a realist!
リアリスト、リアリスト！
Realist, realist!
はいということで、次のお題いきましょ～！
Alright, let's move on to the next topic!
次のお題は…
The next topic is...
写真で一言！！
A photo caption!
お、ということで、その写真見てみましょう！
So, let's take a look at that photo!
どうぞーー！
Here you go!
かわいい！
So cute!
こちらの写真を見て一言お願いしま～す！
Take a look at this photo and give us a caption, please!
え、なんだろう。
What could it be?
奥の方にはなんかこう、
In the back, there's like...
薪が置いてあったりとかして。
firewood piled up and stuff.
ほんとだ。
True.
お庭なんでしょうかね。
I wonder whose yard that is?
はい、ころねさん。
Alright, Korone-san.
ま～きの。
"Makino."
待って、それで行くとさ、後ろの薪も兼ねてるからねw
Wait, if you say that, the firewood in the back is also Makino!
そうそうそうそう！
That's right, that's right!
おい、お前…
"Hey you..."
さっき俺と薪、間違えて燃やしただろ。
"Did you accidentally burn me and the firewood earlier?"
焦げてるでしょ？
It's singed, isn't it?
わぁぁ～！！
Whoa!
そう～、燃やされちゃったんだw焦げたんだよ。
"It got burned!"
可哀想すぎるだろw
That's too pitiful!
可哀想だからやめてください！
It's pitiful, so please stop!
そういう可愛いの出てこないよ～！
Cute things like that don't come out!
精一杯考えたのがこれだったんだよ。
That's what she came up with with all her heart, you know.
はい、精一杯考えた白上さんの答えどうぞ。
Alright, let's hear Shirakami-san's answer.
ゆーちゅーばーの方ですか？
"Are you a YouTuber?"
ふぶちゃん可愛い♡
Fubu-chan, cute!
落としてくれぇぇぇ～!!
Drop us down!!
ゆーちゅーばーの方みたいですね、ということで
Looks like they're YouTubers, so...
皆さん、ケモ耳を3回なでられると何かが起こるらしいですね？
Everyone, if you pet animal ears 3 times, something happens?
「〇ロ」はやめろぉぉ～!!
"Stop with the [Censored]"!
好きだと思ったのに
Even though I thought I liked you...
離れてくれぇぇ!!
Get away from me!!
やめてぇぇぇ!!
Stop it!!
〇リと〇ロ? ねえぇぇ～w
"Guri and Gura"? Heyyy~ lol
うちが実際にナデてみてどういう気持ちになるか
Let's actually pet and see how it feels.
わしゃわしゃわしゃわしゃ…
Pat pat pat pat...
どうでしょうかね？ / 気持ちいい普通に
How is it? / It feels pretty good actually.
ダメだw 気持ちよくなっちゃったw
No good lol, it felt too good lol
わしゃわしゃわしゃ… ミオちゃん気持ちいい…
Pat pat pat... Mio-chan feels good...
吐き気www
Nausea lolol
この流れで?wwww イェアア～!!
In this flow?! Lmao! Yeahhh~!!
わしゃわしゃわしゃわしゃ…
Pat pat pat pat...
願いを一つだけ叶えてやろう…
I shall grant you one wish...
めっちゃおもろいやんww / やったぁぁ～!!
That's hilarious lol / Yayyy~!!
カレーのルーに入ってそうだなって思ったり...
I thought it looked like it goes in curry roux...
思いつかないんだよなぁ…
I just can't think of anything...
お前ら本当に地獄が好きだな編ということで
"You guys really love hell" edition, so...
おもしろかったぁ～
That was fun~
勝ち猫になってますねw
You've become a winning cat lol
じゃあ最後のお題ということで、うちも特別に参加しちゃおうと思いま～す！
Now for the final topic, we'll participate specially too!
今から4人で歌う歌は何でしょうか？
What song will the four of us sing starting now?
大喜利じゃないからね…?!
This isn't Oogiri, you know...?!
できたぁー!
Done!
それではみなさん一斉に出しましょう！せ～の！
Everyone, let's show them all at once! Ready, go!
アイ・ド・ル / アイドル！
A-i-do-ru / Idol!
というわけで、みんなこれから行くよ…！
So everyone, here we go...!
アイドルのポーズ！せーの！アイドル！
Idol pose! Ready, go! Idol!
こんなんじゃねえだろお～!!
That's not what an idol pose is like!!
無敵の笑顔で荒らすメディア
With that invincible smile, you shake up the media
知りたいその秘密ミステリアス
Wanting to know that secret, mysterious
抜けてるとこさえ彼女のエリア
Even your clumsy sides are part of your territory
完璧で嘘つきな君は
You, being flawless and full of lies, are
天才的なアイドル様
An angelic genius idol
今日何食べた?
What did you eat today?
好きな本は?
What book do you love?
遊びに行くならどこに行くの?
Whenever you go out for fun, where do you go?
何も食べてない
Haven't eaten anything
それは内緒
That's a secret
何を聞かれてものらりくらり
Evading whatever you're asked
そう淡々と
So nonchalantly
だけど燦々と見えそうで見えない
Yet brilliantly, almost in sight yet out of reach
秘密は蜜の味
Secrets taste like honey
あれもないないない これもないないない
Nothing at all, none of that either
好きなタイプは? 相手は? さあ答えて
What's your type? Who's your partner? Come on, answer
誰かを好きになることなんて私分からなくてさ
I wouldn't even know what it's like to love someone
嘘か本当か知り得ない そんな言葉にまた一人堕ちる
Falling for words where you can't tell truth from lies
また好きにさせる
Making them fall in love again
誰もが目を奪われていく
Everyone gets completely captivated
君は完璧で究極のアイドル
You are the ultimate, flawless idol
金輪際現れない
The one and only, never to appear again
一番星の生まれ変わり
The reincarnation of the brightest star
ああ、その笑顔で愛してるで
Ah, with that smile saying "I love you"
誰も彼も虜にしていく
Captivating everyone, absolutely everyone
その瞳が その言葉が 嘘でもそれは完全なアイ
Even if those eyes or words are lies, it's pure love
はいはい、あの子は特別です
Yes, yes, that child is special
我々はハナからおまけです
We're just extras from the start
お星様の引き立て役Bです
Just supporting role B to the stars
全てがあの子のお陰なわけない
It can't all be thanks to her
洒落臭い、妬み嫉妬なんてないわけがない
How cheeky, as if jealousy and envy don't exist
これはネタじゃないからこそ許せない
This isn't a joke, that's why we can't forgive it
完璧じゃない君じゃ許せない 自分を許せない
Can't forgive an imperfect you, can't forgive ourselves
誰よりも強い君以外は認めない
We won't accept anyone stronger than you
誰もが信じ崇めてる
Everyone worships and believes in you
まさに最強で無敵のアイドル
Truly the strongest, invincible idol
弱点なんて見当たらない
With no weaknesses to be found
一番星を宿している
Housing the brightest star inside
弱いとこなんて見せちゃダメダメ
Mustn't show any weakness, no no
知られたくないとこは隠さずに? 見せずに?
Hiding parts nobody wants to know? Not showing them?
唯一無二じゃなくちゃイヤイヤ
It has to be one and only, no way
それこそ本物のアイ
That right there is the realest love
得意の笑顔で沸かすメディア
With a triumphant smile, stirring up the media,
隠しきるこの秘密だけは
and keeping this single secret hidden away.
愛してるって嘘で積むキャリア
A career built on the lie of "I love you"—
これこそ私なりの愛だ
this is my own unique form of love.
流れる汗も綺麗なアクア
Even the sweat running down is a clear aqua,
ルビーを隠したこの瞼
hiding the ruby beneath these eyelids.
歌い踊り舞う私はマリア
Singing, dancing, and twirling, I am Maria;
そう嘘はとびきりの愛だ
yes, lying is the ultimate form of love.
誰かに愛されたことも
Having never been loved by anyone,
誰かのこと愛したこともない
nor having ever loved anyone else—
そんな私の嘘がいつか本当になること
believing that my lies will someday become the truth,
信じていつかきっと全部手に入れる
trusting that one day I'll win it all.
私はそう欲張りな
I'm so greedy,
アイドル
an idol,
等身大でみんなのことちゃんと愛したいから
wanting to truly love everyone with my whole self.
今日も嘘をつくの
So today, I tell another lie,
この言葉がいつか本当になる日を願って
hoping for the day these words finally become real.
それでもまだ君にだけは言えずにいたけど
Even so, I couldn't say it to you alone...
やっと言えた これは絶対嘘じゃない
but I finally said it. This is definitely not a lie—
愛してる
I love you.
はーい！
Hii!
ということで、とまどいでアイドルを出してもらいました！いえーい！
So anyway, we had them perform "Idol"! Yay!
ということでしょう！
That's how it is, huh!
なんかさっきまであんな大喜利してたとは思えないような綺麗な歌い方だったよね。
It's hard to believe they were doing improv comedy just a moment ago with such beautiful singing.
ね、でもま、こういうギャップもげまづのいいところでもあるからね。
Right? But you know, that gap is also part of what makes Gamazu great.
いやまじで最高！おめでとうー！
Seriously the best! Congratulations!
そうだよ、おかゆ！
That's right, Okayu!
お誕生日おめでとう！
Happy birthday!
おめでとーー！おめでとーー！
Congratulations! Congratulations!
ちょっとさっきもね、泥賢でお祝いしてもらったのに、もう2回もお祝いしてもらっちゃったよ。
They celebrated me with mud-sages earlier, and now I'm getting celebrated twice!
いや何回でもお祝いするよ、おめでとう！おめでとう！
We'll celebrate as many times as it takes! Happy birthday!
おめでとう！おめでとう！
Congratulations! Congratulations!
おめでとう！おめでとう！おめでとう！
Congratulations! Congratulations! Congratulations!
着替えてきましたー！
I've changed my clothes!
ゲーマーズのみんな、もう行っちゃった……。
Everyone from Gamers already left...
でもさ、でもさ、今年はゲーマーズ年始まってからもうコラボしてるし、今年結構ゲーマーズイヤーになるんじゃない？
But you know, Gamers has been collaborating since the beginning of the year, so this year might really be the Year of Gamers, right?
なんかそんな予感してるよ！ぼくめちゃ楽しみ！
I have a feeling like that! I'm super excited!
よいしょよいしょ、お前じゃ、お前じゃ、待って！
Wait, you guys—wait!
おかにゃあ！なんでいるの？え？え？
Oka-nyan! Why are you here? Eh? Eh?
でもさ、おかにゃあってさ、3Dの体あったっけ？
But wait, did Oka-nyan even have a 3D body?
なかったよね？これもしや初めて？おかにゃあ3D初配信ってこと？
They didn't, right? Is this... Oka-nyan's first 3D stream?
うわ、ぐうしてる、ぐうしてる笑
Whoa, you're doing the "guu" pose lol
え、おかにゃあってこんなに大きかったんだあ！
Eh, Oka-nyan was this big?!
え、何この生々しいカメラ、おかゆには全然必要ないからね！
Eh, what's with this overly realistic camera? Okayu doesn't need this at all!
えー、じゃあでもせっかく来てくれてるし、おかにゃあん、一緒に写真でも撮る？
Eh, well since you came all the way here, Oka-nyan, do you want to take a picture together?
あ、わかった！じゃあなんか無難にピースでもやる？はいちーず！
Oh, I see! Then should we just do a safe peace sign? Cheese!
でっかいなー。なんか足も長いし、ちょっとスタイリッシュなポーズもやってみる？
So big. And your legs are long, do you want to try a stylish pose too?
あ、それね！こうかな？よいしょよいしょ、これ誰がどんないつ使う素材になっちゃうんだろ。
Ah, like that! Is this good? Heh, I wonder what kind of material this will end up being used for.
でもね、あのXの人たちってこういうの好きなんじゃないかな？うんうんうん。
But you know, don't people on X like this kind of stuff? Yeah, yeah.
おかにゃん？おかにゃん？どうしたの？
Oka-nyan? Oka-nyan? What's wrong?
うんうんうんうんうん。
Uh-huh, uh-huh.
ああーー、なるほど！
Aah, I see!
おかにゃんは、実は今日僕のオリジナル曲の発表があって、そのお祝いに来てくれたんだってー！
Oka-nyan apparently came to celebrate the announcement of my original song today!
ありがとーー！じゃあおかにゃんと一緒に新曲踊っていきたいと思います！
Thank you so much! Then let's dance to the new song together with Oka-nyan!
では楽曲発表行きます！新曲はネコカブリーナ！行くよおかにゃん！
Now for the song announcement! The new song is "Neko Kaburiina"! Let's go, Oka-nyan!
生の本音はエグいから
Raw honest feelings are harsh,
ちゃんと火を通して食べてね
so make sure to cook them thoroughly.
リップサービスはズルいかな？
Is lip service a bit unfair?
それも以心伝心のレシピ
That too is a telepathic recipe.
みんな～ 自分 偽ってるかい？
Hey everyone~ Are you faking who you are?
嘘の万国博覧会
A world exposition of lies.
みんな～ 自分 偽ってるかい？
Hey everyone~ Are you faking who you are?
痛みを隠し鳴らして
Hiding the pain and letting it ring out.
嫌いだけど好き 弱くてもおいし
I hate it yet love it, even weak it's delicious.
着ぐるみを着てハグしてあげる
I'll wear a costume and give you a hug.
泣かせないように 怒らせないように
So as not to make you cry or get angry,
ちょうどよく君と遊びたいのだ
I just want to play with you nicely.
ネコカプリーナ ネコカプリーナ
Neko Caprina, Neko Caprina,
ちょっと臆病な君が好き
I like you, a little cowardly.
ネコカプリーナ ネコカプリーナ
Neko Caprina, Neko Caprina,
取り繕ってるぼくが好き？
Do you like the me who puts up a front?
弱さを知ってる君が好きだよ
I love you, who knows what weakness is.
「思う」と言うでは大違い
Saying 'I think' makes all the difference.
建前も用法用量次第
Even pretenses depend on proper dosage.
みんな～ 自分 偽ってるかい？
Hey everyone~ Are you faking who you are?
ひとりぼっちの音楽隊
A lonely marching band.
みんな～ 自分 偽ってるかい？
Hey everyone~ Are you faking who you are?
首輪の鈴鳴らして
Ringing the bell on your collar.
辛いだけどハッピー しんどくても平気
Tough yet happy, even if exhausting it's fine.
アベコベな夢を見せてあげる
I'll show you an upside-down dream.
傷つけないように 追い詰めたないように
So as not to hurt or corner you,
夜明けまで君とふざけ合うのだ
I want to joke around with you until dawn.
ネコカプリーナ ネコカプリーナ
Neko Caprina, Neko Caprina,
爪を丸めてる君が好き
I like you with your claws curled in.
ネコカプリーナ ネコカプリーナ
Neko Caprina, Neko Caprina,
涙を見せないぼくが好き？
Do you like the me who hides my tears?
痛みを知ってる君が好きだよ
I love you, who knows what pain is.
君は猫 猫 ファスナー付きの猫
You are a cat, cat, a zippable cat.
君は人 人 ファスナー付きの人
You are a person, person, a zippable person.
あれはUFO UFO ファスナー付きのUFO
That's a UFO, UFO, a zippable UFO.
君は猫 猫 ファスナー付きの猫
You are a cat, cat, a zippable cat.
君は人 人 ファスナー付きの人
You are a person, person, a zippable person.
あれはUFO UFO ファスナー付きのUFO
That's a UFO, UFO, a zippable UFO.
君は誰 誰 特別な人
Who are you, who? A special person.
ネコカプリーナ ネコカプリーナ
Neko Caprina, Neko Caprina,
ちょっと臆病な君が好き
I like you, a little cowardly.
君もぼくも馴染めない世界で
In this world where neither of us fits in,
やっと見つけた居場所だから
this is the place we finally found.
ネコカプリーナ ネコカプリーナ
Neko Caprina, Neko Caprina,
取り繕ってるぼくが好き？
Do you like the me who puts up a front?
君もぼくもどうかしる世界で 明日もまた会えたらいいな
In this crazy world for both of us, I hope we can meet again tomorrow.
ネコカプリーナ ネコカプリーナ
Neko Caprina, Neko Caprina,
弱さを知ってる君が好きだよ
I love you, who knows what weakness is.
みんな！ありがとう！
Everyone! Thank you!
僕の2024年3Dライブ「キャットフード」、どうだったかな？楽しんで、笑えたかな？
How was my 2024 3D live "Cat Food"? Did you enjoy it and have fun?
後日、僕の配信でいろいろ裏話とか話せたらいいなって思うよ！
I hope to share various behind-the-scenes stories on my stream later!
みんな、まだ帰らないで！このあと重大な告知があるから！またねー！
Everyone, don't leave yet! There's a major announcement coming up! See you later!
はーい、みんな！生誕祭ライブ楽しんでもらえたかな？
Hi everyone! Did you enjoy the birthday live?
今お披露目させていただいた僕の新オリジナル曲「ネコカプリーナ」はこの後21時からプレミア公開されます！
My new original song "Neko Caprina" which I just unveiled will premiere tonight at 9 PM!
猫又おかゆ史上初めてのフルアニメMVとなりますので、みんなにいっぱい楽しんで欲しい！
It's Nekomata Okayu's very first full-anime music video, so I hope you all enjoy it to the fullest!
楽曲は「モグモグYAMMY」でもお馴染みピノキオピー様に書いていただきました！
The song was written by PinocchioP, whom you know from "Mogu Mogu YAMMY"!
可愛らしく何度何度も聞きたくなること間違いなし！
It's so cute you'll definitely want to listen to it over and over again!
この後24時から各種音楽サイトでも配信がありますよ！
It will also be available on various music streaming sites starting at midnight!
続いての告知です。なんと！
Here is the next announcement. Guess what!
全国のアミューズメント施設で稼働中の「サウンドボルテックス」と僕のコラボが開催中！わーい！
My collaboration with "Sound Voltex", currently operating in amusement facilities nationwide, is underway! Yay!
僕がネメシスクルーとしておにぎりゃーたちをボイス付きでサポートしちゃうよ！
I'll be supporting Onigirya as a Nemesis Crew with voice lines!
詳細はこちら！期間限定で猫又おかゆプレミアムジェネレーターが登場！ボイス付きアピールスタンプやホログラムの名シーンや僕のメ...
Details are right here! The limited-time Nekomata Okayu Premium Generator is here! Featuring voiced appeal stamps, holographic memorable scenes, and my...
ボイスがもらえるムービー壁紙などの豪華コラボアイテムもゲットできちゃうんだ！
You can also get gorgeous collaboration items like...
そして、
And then,
e-amusement passカードプレゼントキャンペーンも開催中！
e-amusement pass card present campaign is also underway!
SOUND VOLTEXのデータを保存するのに必要なカードをボクのデザインでゲットできちゃうよ！
You can get cards with my design needed to save SOUND VOLTEX data!
さらに！抽選でe-amusement passカードが当たるキャンペーンも開催中！
What's more, a campaign where you can win an e-amusement pass card by drawing is also being held!
SOUND VOLTEX公式Xアカウントのチェックを忘れずにね！
Don't forget to check your SOUND VOLTEX official X account!
最後に、「もぐもぐYUMMY！」
Finally, "Mogu Mogu YUMMY!",
「毒杯スワロウ」「カミサマネコサマ」の3曲が
"Dokuhai Swallow", and "Kamisama Nekosama", three songs,
SOUND VOLTEXに本日(きょう)から収録！
are available in SOUND VOLTEX starting today!
たくさんプレイしてほしいな！
I hope you'll play them a lot!
以上、SOUND VOLTEXのお知らせでした！
That's all for the SOUND VOLTEX announcement.
続いてはお楽しみ、新グッズのお知らせです。
Next is the long-awaited announcement for new goods!
たくさんアイデアを練り練りしたよ！
I've brainstormed and put together lots of ideas!
まずは、こちら。
First is this.
おかゆとおそろいパーカー！
Matching parka with Okayu!
ついに！皆さん待望であっただろう、ねこまたおかゆパーカー！胸にスタイリッシュな角度のおにぎりがプリントされているよ。
It's the Nekomata Okayu Parka that everyone has been waiting for, featuring stylishly angled rice balls printed on the chest!
ホロライブのイベントに着て行くもよし、飾ってボクと一緒に生活してる感じを楽しむのもよし。
It's great for wearing to Hololive events or enjoying the feeling of living together with me.
運営さんと再現を目指すために、タグや生地にもこだわりました！
We even paid attention to the tags to aim for official merch quality!
続いて、
Next up...
おにぎりぬいぐるみ！
Rice ball plushie!
ボクのぬいぐるみは結構出てるけど、やっぱりおにぎりのぬいぐるみも欲しいよね！
My plushies are already out there, but of course, rice ball plushies are a must-have too!
今まで販売してたおかゆぬいぐるみと並べてみても、いい感じになるサイズにしてみたよ。
Compared to previously sold Okayu plushies, I made it a nice size.
デスクや寝室、飾りたいとこに置ける自立型のぬいぐるみ！
It's a self-standing plushie that looks great on your desk or in your bedroom.
支えがなくても座ってくれる！ぜひ僕のぬいと一緒に並べてみてね！
Even without support, it sits down! Please line it up with my plushies!
続きましては、ついにやつがグッズ化します！
And then, finally, a new goods item is here!
どん！
Ta-da!
おかニャンタンブラー「WAIYADE」
Okayan Tumbler "WAIYADE"!
なんと！ホロライブ史上初めてのおかニャンングッズが登場だ！
Incredible! The very first Okayan goods in Hololive history are here!
おかニャンファンの根強い希望によりグッズ化させていただきました！
Made possible by the passionate wishes of Okayan fans, we were able to make it happen!
家でもオフィスでも使いやすいように、シンプルかつ少し控えめにおかニャンが君を応援してくれるよ。メタリックカラーなオシャレタンブラーでやる気がみなぎる！
To make it easy to use at home or in the office, it's a simple yet slightly subtle design where Okayan gently cheers you on.
お次は、
Next is...
「ネコカプリーナ」公開記念アクリルスタンド！
Acrylic stand for the "Nekopurina" release!
こちら、この後公開されるアニメMV仕様となっております。
This features the design for the upcoming anime MV release!
今回ののアニメMVでもキャラクターデザインを担当してくださった愛音Kosen先生にイラスト原画をお願いしました！か、かわいすぎる……！
For this anime MV, character design was done by Aine Kosen-sensei, who also drew the illustration. It's so cute!
アニメMVオリジナルの衣装なので、文字文字と見てほしいな。
It's an original outfit from the anime MV, so I hope you'll check out every single detail!
そして、最後はですね！
And finally...
じゃじゃーん！
Ta-da!
今回、フルセット購入していただいた方には特典があります！直筆サイン入りチェキ風ブロマイドカードがついてくるよ！
This time, everyone who purchases the full set will get a special bonus: an autographed Instax-style bromide card!
購入制限は、無制限！
There is no purchase limit!
買ってくれた人みんなに僕のサインが届くよ！愛情たっぷりのサイン書かせていただきます！
My autograph will reach everyone who buys it, and I'll write each one with all my love!
ということで、グッズのおしらせでした！
That's all for the goods announcement!
みんなよかったらお迎えしてね！
If you'd like, please come pick them up!
それでは、このあと最高の動畫アニメMV「ネコカプリーナ」のプレミア公開をぜひ観にいってみてね！
Well then, after this, please be sure to go check out the premiere of the best anime MV, "Nekopurina"!
それでは、お疲れさまでした！
Good work, everyone!
かんしょく、おかゆー！
Enjoy, Okayu!